

DATA SCIENCE AND ANALYTICS LEADER

Chicago, IL, USA

📕 616.706.3471 | 💌 jim.kloet@gmail.com | 🖸 jimtheflash | 🛅 jimkloet | 💆 @jimkloet

## Summary\_

Hi, I'm Jim! I'm passionate about helping people and organizations make better decisions. So far, I've accomplished this by building and leading teams of talented data professionals across several industries, e-comm, consumer goods, healthcare, and academic research. Let's talk!

## **Experience**

Reverb Chicago, IL, USA

MANAGER, Product Analytics & Data Science

2021 - present

2019 - 2021

- Lead team of data scientists and analysts to support product experimentation and data science initiatives across the organization
- Develop and support automated tooling in python and R for analyzing and reporting on experiments and tracking progress toward goals
- · Manage development and deployment of all machine learning models in production, in collaboration with Data Engineering

**ABC Supply Co.** Chicago, IL, USA

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST, IT Data Science · Led data science initiatives across several domains, including workforce management, associate retention, security, and e-comm

- Developed project plans and supervise students and interns on capstone projects and hackathons with university partners
- · Created and disseminated standards and best practices in data visualization and code management with R packages

Nielsen Chicago, IL, USA

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST, Data Science as a Service

2019 - 2019

- · Led engagements for Data Science as a Service team in the consumer packaged goods space
- Developed containerized pipelines to ETL data to and from AWS environments using python
- · Generated recommendations for optimal nationwide pricing and promotion strategies, delivered via Tableau dashboard

Mattersight Chicago, IL, USA

DIRECTOR OF INSIGHTS & ANALYTICS, SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

2015 - 2019

- · Led team of data scientists and analysts responsible for reporting and ad-hoc analysis for all subscription clients
- · Developed analytic tools in R and SQL to scale implementation of best practices in statistical analyses and data visualization
- · Automated client-facing reporting, enabling data scientists and analysts to reallocate hundreds of hours away from manual report generation
- Led presentations for clients and internal audiences on development and use cases for predictive analytics, esp. predictive CX measures

**RotoViz** 

DIRECTOR OF VISUAL APPLICATIONS, CONTRIBUTING WRITER

2013 - 2019

- · Develop web applications to give users insights into performance of professional sports teams and players
- Train new writers and developers in data science and data visualization methods using R

**Northwestern University** Evanston, IL, USA

TRANSLATIONAL RESEARCH FELLOW, DOCTORAL CANDIDATE, RESEARCH TECHNICIAN, Communication Sciences & Disorders

2009 - 2015

- Designed, executed, and analyzed experiments to investigate language and learning in the brain using fMRI and rTMS
- · Presented experimental results at conferences, invited lectures, and in peer-reviewed publications
- · Delivered lectures to undergraduate and graduate students on topics in cognitive neuroscience and stats

Skills\_

**Programming** R, SQL, Python, git, Matlab, LTEX

**Big Data** Azure, DataBricks, Hive, Impala, Hue, Beeline

**Education** 

**Northwestern University** 

MA, PHD (ALL BUT DISSERTATION), Cognitive Science, Communication Sciences & Disorders

Evanston, IL, USA

2015

**University of Michigan** Ann Arbor, MI, USA

BA, Psychology 2006

JIM KLOET RESUME MAY 29, 2023